Dylan Toporek

Syracuse, New York 13202 | 917-495-6908 | dylantoporek@gmail.com

Github | Blog | Linkedin

JOB TITLE

Full stack web developer with a background in education. Experienced in Ruby on Rails, React, and JavaScript based programming. Possess strong skills in team-building, project management, creativity, and adaptability. Continuously pushing myself to achieve higher goals, I will take all my enthusiasm and motivation and apply it to your team. I have a passion for games, from their logic systems to mechanics, I find myself always trying to learn each tiny detail.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript, React, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Microsoft Office

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Breath of the Wild Cooking App - Demo | Frontend Git Repo | Backend Git Repo

A cooking mini-game simulating an online shop with a cart and checkout. Buy ingredients and cook them!

- Backend built with Ruby on Rails, utilizing React and custom CSS for the frontend.
- Persisted user data in the backend using ActiveRecord.
- Scraped images and information from https://zelda.fandom.com/wiki/Main_Page to use as seeds.
- Fetched and reformatted the recipes from https://zelda-cookbook-backend.herokuapp.com/.

Nintendo Land - Demo | Frontend Git Repo | Backend Git Repo

A board game where you race to the finish against three computer opponents.

- Backend built with Ruby on Rails, utilizing React and custom CSS for the frontend.
- Persisted user data in the backend using ActiveRecord.
- Fetched character piece images from https://amiiboapi.com/.
- Used promise objects to achieve asynchronous functionality for each turn.

EXPERIENCE

The Flatiron School Software Engineering Bootcamp Student

New York, NY

09/2021 - 03/2022

- Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript programming
- Experience with React for frontend development and Ruby on Rails for backend development

Private Tutor and Homeschool Teacher

New York, NY

Tutor / Teacher

2017 - Present

- Offered academic support in various subjects
- Aided students in organization of school work
- Facilitated contact with school teachers and administration to ensure seamless schooling experience
- Ensured maintenance of school work in students unable to attend due to illness

MathnasiumNew York, NYInstructor2016 - Present

Math instructor at busy after school mathematics instruction company

The Collegiate School

New York, NY

Math Teacher

01/2020 - 06/2020

- Math teacher of two 7th grade classes
- Prepared all course work, classroom activities, and assessments

The Birch Wathen Lenox School

New York, NY

Math Teacher

01/2017 - 06/2017

- Assistant math teacher / permanent substitute for maternity leave teacher
- Prepared class materials, assisted in four class sections (two 6th grade, one 7th grade, and one 9th grade sections) in addition to grading assignments

EDUCATION

University of Massachusetts Amherst, College of Social and Behavioral Sciences

Amherst, MA